Carleen Thio

A designer passionate about creating better user experience through problem-solving and empathy.

• Toronto, ON

✓ carleen.thio@gmail.com

647.500.8188

http://carleenthio.github.io/

Education

George Brown · Present

UX Design Certificate

University of Toronto · 2019

Honours Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Science (specializing in Computational Cognition) and Linguistic

About Me

I like research and usability test — it lets me experiment and learn more about the world and people who live in it. I believe that helps build understanding and empathy.

I'm currently a Live Green Toronto volunteer. Previously volunteering for the Toronto Animal Service.

Also a major boardgame fan, especially co-op or strategy ones.

Skills

Tools Figma Sketch Axure Adobe XD Axure

UX Design

Wireframing Prototyping
User Research Usability Testing
Microcopy Interaction Design

Programming



Other

Agile Git LaTeX

Design Projects

UX Designer (Contractor) | Local Deals - Figma

Nov. 2020 - Dec. 2020 (Remote - Toronto, ON)

Designed a local deals web application that combines the functionality of Groupon and Classified Ads. Collaborated with the developer to produce an intuitive mobile and desktop web app for Buyers and Businesses.

UX Designer (Contractor) | Scout Social - Figma

Apr. 2020 - Jul. 2020 (Remote - Toronto, ON)

Designed a web dashboard for admins and a mobile app for influencers. Created high-fidelity wireframes and clickable prototypes for the software developer and client.

UX Researcher | Füdger - Axure RP

Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019 (Toronto, ON)

Developed a low-fidelity paper prototype and a high-fidelity prototype mobile app, based on research findings, which help users keep track of their inventory and grocery list. Conducted field studies, performed usability testing on both prototypes (guerilla testing), and a heuristic evaluation.

UX/UI Designer (Freelancer) | Thullus Cafe - Figma

Nov. 2020 - Now (Remote)

Redesigned the existing menu and improve the menu's information architecture. Aided in creating the cafe's brand strategy.

UX Researcher | Kallie - Adobe XD

Dec. 2019 - Mar. 2020 (Remote)

Designed and tested a low-fidelity scheduling app prototype for the trading and plant community. Guided the team through gathering business requirements, conducting user research and competitive analysis to create personas, user journeys, and task flows.

UX/UI Designer & Web Developer | My portfolio - Figma

Nov. 2019 - Present (Toronto, ON)

Designed, coded, and deployed a responsive website on Github Pages.

Work Experience

Game Designer | Clipwire - Figma & Adobe XD

Jun. 2020 - Nov. 2020 (Toronto, ON)

- Designed and wireframed events, improvements, and new features for Bingo Story.
- Documented new designs in a game design document.
- Conceptualized A/B tests that increased overall user engagement.
- Worked on audio design and playtesting.
- Scheduled in-game content and marketing campaigns for upcoming events.

UX Designer & Content Writer | Private Clients

Jan. 2020 - Present (Toronto, ON)

- Designed wireframes and prototypes for various client projects.
- Wrote UX case studies for my UX/Product designer client's portfolio.
- Create content based on client requirements and provide creative suggestions to improve content flow.

Favourite projects to date:

- Crafted over 800 sentences for Typing Master's games, which helps improve children's typing skills.
- Created and edited content for a gratitude chatbot for a natural conversational flow.